<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Max Online Mills</title>
	<atom:link href="https://max.online.mills.edu/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://max.online.mills.edu</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 13:35:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://max.online.mills.edu/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/MAX2.png</url>
	<title>Max Online Mills</title>
	<link>https://max.online.mills.edu</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Seven die as cyclone barrels towards western India, Pakistan</title>
		<link>https://max.online.mills.edu/seven-die-as-cyclone-barrels-towards-western-india-pakistan/</link>
					<comments>https://max.online.mills.edu/seven-die-as-cyclone-barrels-towards-western-india-pakistan/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admisst]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 13:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cyclone]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost/polkatua/?p=30</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Four boys drowned in rough seas off the western Indian financial hub of Mumbai on...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Four boys drowned in rough seas off the western Indian financial hub of Mumbai on Tuesday as India and Pakistan began evacuating people from coastal areas, two days before a cyclone is expected to make landfall.</p>



<p>Classified as a very severe cyclonic storm, Biparjoy is expected to land around Thursday evening between Mandvi in India&#8217;s Gujarat province and Karachi in southern Pakistan.</p>



<p>Meteorologists predict maximum sustained wind speeds of 125-135 km (78-84 miles) per hour, gusting to 150 km (93 miles) per hour.</p>



<p>&#8220;Four boys drowned at Juhu beach on Monday evening. So far, we have found the bodies of two, and the search is still ongoing to locate the remaining two,&#8221; said a police official in Mumbai, south of Gujarat.</p>



<p>High waves in the Arabian Sea, accompanied by heavy rains and gusting winds pounded Gujarat&#8217;s coastal areas, uprooting trees and resulting in a wall collapse that killed three people in Kutch and Rajkot districts, authorities said.</p>



<p>Eight districts in coastal Gujarat are expected to be affected, the state government said. Fishing has been suspended until Friday and schools have declared holidays.</p>



<p>Gujarat is home to many offshore oil installations and major ports in the country and most have been forced to suspend operations.</p>



<p>A 1998 cyclone killed at least 4,000 people and caused hundreds of millions of dollars of damage in Gujarat.</p>



<p>Relief Commissioner Alok Kumar Pandey said that more than 20,500 people have been evacuated from coastal districts and the evacuation was expected to be completed by Tuesday evening.</p>



<p>In neighbouring Pakistan, paramilitary troops and local civil authorities also started moving people to shelters and relief camps, which were set up in schools and other government buildings, said Climate Change Minister Sherry Rehman.</p>



<p>Ships and boats have been moved from some areas of Pakistan&#8217;s coast while hospitals in the region were put on high alert, added Rehman.</p>



<p>About 100,000 people will be evacuated by Wednesday morning, the chairman of Pakistan&#8217;s National Disaster Management Authority said.</p>



<p>Two of India&#8217;s largest ports, Kandla and Mundra, have suspended operations, the state government said. Other ports, including Bedi, Navlakhi, Porbandar, Okha, Pipavav and Bhavnagar, have also closed due to the cyclone, according to shipping sources.</p>



<p>Reliance Industries, which operates the world&#8217;s largest refining complex in Gujarat&#8217;s Jamnagar, declared a force majeure, suspending exports of diesel and other oil products from Gujarat&#8217;s Sikka port, traders said.</p>



<p>The Adani conglomerate&#8217;s ports business, Adani Ports (APSE.NS), said it suspended vessel operations on Monday at Mundra, India&#8217;s biggest commercial port that has the country&#8217;s largest coal import terminal, and also at Tuna port near Kandla.</p>



<p>The Indian Coast Guard said it evacuated 50 personnel from a jack-up oil rig off Gujarat&#8217;s coast named Key Singapore, which is owned by Dubai-based Shelf Drilling and currently working for Cairn Oil &amp; Gas, according to Shelf Drilling&#8217;s website.</p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://max.online.mills.edu/seven-die-as-cyclone-barrels-towards-western-india-pakistan/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Najmul century helps Bangladesh post 362-5 at day one</title>
		<link>https://max.online.mills.edu/najmul-century-helps-bangladesh-post-362-5-at-day-one/</link>
					<comments>https://max.online.mills.edu/najmul-century-helps-bangladesh-post-362-5-at-day-one/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admisst]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 13:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Afghanistan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bangladesh]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Test]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost/polkatua/?p=25</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Bangladesh batter Najmul Hossain scored a brisk century in the first day of their one-off...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Bangladesh batter Najmul Hossain scored a brisk century in the first day of their one-off Test against Afghanistan at the Sher-e-Bangla National Stadium on Wednesday to put his team on a vantage position.</p>



<p>The left-handed batter made 146 runs off 175 balls and put up a big partnership of 212 runs with young opener Mahmudul Hasan to help Bangladesh reach 362-5 at stumps.</p>



<p>Thanks to the partnership of Najmul and Mahmudul, who scored 76, Bangladesh were at a stage on 218-1 and looked to set a mammoth total but visitors pulled off things a little bit early in the final session.</p>



<p>Some careless shots from Bangladesh batters and spirited bowling from Afghans saw Bangladesh reduced to 290-5 but experienced batter Mushfiqur Rahim and Mehidy Hasan formed a stubborn stand to see off the day. Afghan bowlers, who looked sloppy and extremely indiscipline most of the day, could bowl only 79 overs instead of 90 despite having consumed an extra half an hour.</p>



<p>Earlier on the day Afghan bowler Nijat Masood had a dream start in his Test career as he got rid of opener Zakir Hasan in his very first delivery. Zakir got out for one as the score was 6-1 in 1.1 overs and the decision of Afghan skipper Hashmatullah Shahidi of bowling first seemed a good one.</p>



<p>But Najmul started attacking against the wayward bowling of the visitors’ picking boundaries in almost every other over while Mahmudul helped him forge a lethal stand by remaining solid.</p>



<p>Najmul, who seems to be in the form of his life across the formats, was aggressive both against pacers and spinners to reach his third Test ton with the aid of 18 boundaries.</p>



<p>Afghan bowlers not only bowled with poor line and length but also conceded a lot of no balls (15) as Bangladeshi pairs seemed to bat as long as they wished.</p>



<p>But Mahmudul played a sloppy shot off occasional leg-spinner Rahmat Shah when his attempted cut found an edge through to Ibrahim Zadran at slip.</p>



<p>Despite the wicket bowling continued to be flat and new batter Mominul Haque seemed well settled but former Bangladesh skipper nicked a ball off Masood which was going down the leg to be caught by wicketkeeper Zazai for 15.</p>



<p>Najmul got a reprieve as he was bowled by Masood but the replay showed the bowler overstepped when he was 143 in the 55th over but three overs later he lost his patience under scorching sun and stepped down against leg spinner Amir Hamza to be holed on in the long on by Nasir Jamal.</p>



<p>Liton Das, who is captaining the Test side for the first time, looked nervous and threw away his wicket when he tried for a mistimed drive against and innocuous delivery of chinaman bowler Zahir Khan to be caught behind for just nine.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://max.online.mills.edu/najmul-century-helps-bangladesh-post-362-5-at-day-one/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>An 8-year-old child lifts 60 kg</title>
		<link>https://max.online.mills.edu/an-8-year-old-child-lifts-60-kg/</link>
					<comments>https://max.online.mills.edu/an-8-year-old-child-lifts-60-kg/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admisst]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 08:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[international]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weight lifting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Weird news]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost/asfdgdfhnow/?p=16</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Arshiya Goswami is eight years old. He has taken the internet by storm with his...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Arshiya Goswami is eight years old. He has taken the internet by storm with his weightlifting prowess. This child from Panchkula, Haryana state of India has recently lifted 60 kg.</p>



<p>In a video posted on social media Instagram, Arsia can be seen lifting 60 kg. He succeeded in one attempt. After lifting the weight, holding it for a while and throwing it away. After that, Arshiya is coming towards the camera in a very confident manner. Its caption read, &#8216;A very young and strong baby girl.&#8217;</p>



<p>Four days ago this video of Arsiya was released. It received more than 23 thousand responses. And the video has been viewed more than two and a half million times. Many have praised him in the comments section. One wrote, what enthusiasm, confidence. Another wrote, &#8216;One day India will be proud of you.&#8217; A third person wrote, &#8216;Much respect to you. Many adults will not be able to lift this amount of weight.&#8217;</p>



<p>Russia wants to participate in the Olympics. He is moving forward in that direction. This is why regular weight lifting. At the age of six, he won a medal in India in 2021 by lifting 45 kg. And for this extraordinary work, he got his name in the India Book of Records.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://max.online.mills.edu/an-8-year-old-child-lifts-60-kg/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Erdoğan wanted F-16 fighter jets, Biden gave conditions</title>
		<link>https://max.online.mills.edu/erdogan-wanted-f-16-fighter-jets-biden-gave-conditions/</link>
					<comments>https://max.online.mills.edu/erdogan-wanted-f-16-fighter-jets-biden-gave-conditions/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admisst]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 08:50:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fighter plane]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Joe Biden]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NATO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recep Tayyip Erdogan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Türkiye]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost/asfdgdfhnow/?p=11</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Turkish President Recep Tayyip Erdogan wants to buy advanced F-16 fighter jets from the United...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Turkish President Recep Tayyip Erdogan wants to buy advanced F-16 fighter jets from the United States. He told US President Joe Biden about this interest. But Biden gave him a counter condition. Turkey has objected to Sweden&#8217;s application to become a member of the Western military alliance NATO. Biden wants, Erdoğan will remove this objection.</p>



<p>Erdogan has dominated Turkish politics for two decades. First he was the Prime Minister of the country, then he became the President. He was elected as the President of Turkey for the third term last Sunday. Erdogan will lead the country with an important position in the international arena for the next five years.</p>



<p>Biden called yesterday Monday to congratulate Erdoğan after winning the election. In this phone conversation, Erdogan reiterated Ankara&#8217;s interest in buying F-16 fighter jets. Biden also informed him of Washington&#8217;s interest in NATO and the Sweden issue. Biden himself told the media about this conversation.</p>



<p>Yesterday, Biden told reporters at the White House, &#8216;I spoke with Erdogan. I congratulated Erdoğan. He (Erdoğan) still wants to do some work on F-16 fighter jets. I told him, we want an agreement with Sweden. Let&#8217;s do it together. We will get back to each other about it.&#8217;</p>



<p>Do you expect Erdoğan to take any initiative on Sweden joining NATO? Reporters ask Biden. In response, Biden said, &#8216;I raised the issue with him (Erdoğan). There will be further discussions between the US and Turkey on this next week.&#8217;</p>



<p>Sweden and Finland have been following the principle of neutrality in international politics for a long time. But after the beginning of the Russian attack on Ukraine in February last year, there was a change in the neutral policy of the two countries. Finland and Sweden think that Moscow can attack their countries as well. So the two countries want to join NATO for advance security. Because, if a member country is attacked, the rest of the NATO members will respond simultaneously. This is the rule of this military alliance.</p>



<p>Sweden and Finland applied to join NATO last year. Türkiye objected. Another NATO rule is that adding new members requires the consent of all existing members. So the initiative got stuck due to the obstruction of NATO member Turkey.</p>



<p>Later, after muddling the waters, Türkiye became flexible about Finland. Removed the objection. As a result, Finland joined NATO. But Erdogan&#8217;s Türkiye is still adamant about Sweden. Sweden&#8217;s application is also pending. So now the US, the most influential member of NATO, is trying to convince Erdogan about Sweden.</p>



<p>Meanwhile, Turkey&#8217;s interest in buying F-16 fighter jets from the US is quite old. The country is also willing to spend 2 billion dollars for this. But the US Congress objected. According to Congress, Ankara has not yet given the green signal for NATO expansion. Apart from this, questions remain about Erdoğan&#8217;s Syria policy and Turkey&#8217;s human rights situation. Therefore, the US Congress does not want to sell F-16 to Ankara for now.</p>



<p>Meanwhile, Erdoğan&#8217;s office issued a statement regarding the phone conversation with Biden. It is said that the two leaders have agreed to deepen cooperation on bilateral issues. This bilateral relationship will play an important role in meeting regional and global challenges.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://max.online.mills.edu/erdogan-wanted-f-16-fighter-jets-biden-gave-conditions/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Who won the prize in IPL and how much money did they get?</title>
		<link>https://max.online.mills.edu/who-won-the-prize-in-ipl-and-how-much-money-did-they-get/</link>
					<comments>https://max.online.mills.edu/who-won-the-prize-in-ipl-and-how-much-money-did-they-get/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admisst]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 08:47:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chennai Super Kings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gujarat Titans]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IPL]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost/asfdgdfhnow/?p=8</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Is this the best season in IPL history? Is this the best final in IPL...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Is this the best season in IPL history? Is this the best final in IPL history? If you keep track of the whole tournament and watch last night&#8217;s Ruddhaswath final, most of the cricket fans will probably say &#8216;yes&#8217; to these two questions.</p>



<p>Returning to the home-away format after 4 years after dealing with the shock of Corona, Rinku Singh hitting five sixes in the last five balls to win the team, Virat Kohli regaining himself, Faf du Plessis&#8217; old bone Velki, Yasswi Jaiswal -Akash Madhwal&#8217;s rise, Shubman Gill&#8217;s incredible form, on the third day Ravindra Jadeja&#8217;s steely nerves with 10 runs in the last 2 balls of the made final and Mahendra Singh Dhoni&#8217;s surprise to win the title &#8211; what was not in this IPL?</p>



<p>The surprise was also the prize money of the tournament. The Indian Cricket Board (BCCI) has given a record prize money of more than 60 crore 31 lakh rupees in this season, which is more than the last T20 World Cup held in Australia in October-November last year! The ICC gave a total of 60.3 million rupees in financial prizes in the World Cup.</p>



<p>This year&#8217;s champion Dhoni&#8217;s Chennai Super Kings got Tk 25 crore 94 lakh, runner-up Gujarat Titans got Tk 16 crore 86 lakh. Apart from this, awards were given in many other categories including highest run scorer, highest wicket taker, best player of the tournament.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://max.online.mills.edu/who-won-the-prize-in-ipl-and-how-much-money-did-they-get/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
