<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>child &#8211; Bs Online Mills</title>
	<atom:link href="https://bs.online.mills.edu/tag/child/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://bs.online.mills.edu</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2023 17:04:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://bs.online.mills.edu/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/mils.png</url>
	<title>child &#8211; Bs Online Mills</title>
	<link>https://bs.online.mills.edu</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>40 days in the Amazon: Four children survived by eating cassava flour, fruit</title>
		<link>https://bs.online.mills.edu/40-days-in-the-amazon-four-children-survived-by-eating-cassava-flour-fruit/</link>
					<comments>https://bs.online.mills.edu/40-days-in-the-amazon-four-children-survived-by-eating-cassava-flour-fruit/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[aminsa]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2023 17:04:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[amazon forest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[America]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[child]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the amazon]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bs.online.mills.edu/?p=216</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Four children who spent more than a month in the Amazon jungle after a plane crash survived mainly on cassava flour. When that flour ran out, they survived by gathering fruits in the forest. The Colombian army and the relatives of the children reported this information. Colombian army spokesman Sánchez Suarez told reporters that the...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Four children who spent more than a month in the Amazon jungle after a plane crash survived mainly on cassava flour. When that flour ran out, they survived by gathering fruits in the forest. The Colombian army and the relatives of the children reported this information.</p>



<p>Colombian army spokesman Sánchez Suarez told reporters that the children had eaten three kilograms of &#8216;farina&#8217;. Farina is a type of cassava flour, which is not as smooth. This food is eaten by indigenous communities in the Amazon region.</p>



<p>The army spokesman said that the children ate the food they had taken with them for several days after the plane crashed. When food runs out, they start looking for places where they can survive.</p>



<p>On May 1, the four children were going to San Jose del Guaviare from Araracuara village in the Amazon region by plane with their mother. The small Cessna single-engine plane was carrying three adults and four children. The pilot declared an emergency due to engine failure. After a while it lost contact with the radar.</p>



<p>The children&#8217;s mother Magdalena Mukutui Valencia, pilot Hernando Murcia Morales and Herman Mendeza Hernandez, leader of an indigenous community, died in the plane crash. The children were left alone in the deep forest. The four children from the Huitoto community are aged 13, 9 and 4 years respectively and the other is an 11-month-old newborn.</p>



<p>The search for the passengers of the plane started after the accident. They were rescued from a place within 5 km of the accident site on Friday. They are currently admitted to a hospital in Bogota, the capital of Colombia. Colombian government officials and military officials visited the hospital on Saturday, along with relatives of the children.</p>



<p>Standing outside the hospital, the children&#8217;s uncle, Fidencio Valencia, told reporters that they pulled Farina from the wreckage of the plane after it crashed. They survive by eating them. When the farina was over, they began to eat the fruits of the forest.</p>



<p>Cassava is basically a type of root potato. It is cultivated in hilly, uncultivated and relatively less fertile land. In Bangladesh it is also known as &#8216;Shimul Alu&#8217;. In recent years, its cultivation has increased in Bangladesh.</p>



<p>Colombian army spokesman Sanchez Suarez said when they found the four children in the jungle, they looked malnourished. But they had knowledge and could speak clearly. He said, &#8216;Due to being a tribal family, their bodies had already developed resistance to some forest-based diseases. Apart from that, they had many ideas about what can be eaten and what cannot be eaten in the forest. Apart from this, they have been able to survive due to access to water. If they were not familiar with these things, they could not survive in such a hostile environment.&#8217;</p>



<p>Army officials said, after rescuing the children, they were taken to the Bogota hospital by air ambulance on Saturday. After visiting the children in the hospital, Colombia&#8217;s Defense Minister Ivan Valesquez told reporters that they were dehydrated. They still can&#8217;t eat anything. But they are fine and out of harm&#8217;s way now.</p>



<p>An extensive search of the Amazon was conducted to find these children. In addition to more than a hundred members of the Colombian Special Forces, 70 members of scouts from the indigenous community continued to search the deep jungle. The children told officers they came across a search dog. It was a Belgian Shepherd. Army spokesman Sanchez Suarez said the special forces dog went missing on May 18. &#8216;The children told us they were with the dog named Wilson for three to four days. They found the dog in a very weak physical condition,&#8217; he said. &nbsp;</p>



<p>As weeks went by in the search, hope of finding these children faded. Their return there has caused a great response among the people of Colombia. President Gustavo Petro visited the hospital yesterday to see the children. He said, their survival in the Amazon jungle will be remembered in history.</p>



<p>&#8216;They were children of the forest. Now they are the children of Colombia,&#8217; said the President.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://bs.online.mills.edu/40-days-in-the-amazon-four-children-survived-by-eating-cassava-flour-fruit/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
