<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Türkiye &#8211; Max Online Mills</title>
	<atom:link href="https://max.online.mills.edu/tag/turkiye/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://max.online.mills.edu</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 08:50:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://max.online.mills.edu/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/MAX2.png</url>
	<title>Türkiye &#8211; Max Online Mills</title>
	<link>https://max.online.mills.edu</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Erdoğan wanted F-16 fighter jets, Biden gave conditions</title>
		<link>https://max.online.mills.edu/erdogan-wanted-f-16-fighter-jets-biden-gave-conditions/</link>
					<comments>https://max.online.mills.edu/erdogan-wanted-f-16-fighter-jets-biden-gave-conditions/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admisst]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 08:50:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fighter plane]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Joe Biden]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NATO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recep Tayyip Erdogan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Türkiye]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost/asfdgdfhnow/?p=11</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Turkish President Recep Tayyip Erdogan wants to buy advanced F-16 fighter jets from the United...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Turkish President Recep Tayyip Erdogan wants to buy advanced F-16 fighter jets from the United States. He told US President Joe Biden about this interest. But Biden gave him a counter condition. Turkey has objected to Sweden&#8217;s application to become a member of the Western military alliance NATO. Biden wants, Erdoğan will remove this objection.</p>



<p>Erdogan has dominated Turkish politics for two decades. First he was the Prime Minister of the country, then he became the President. He was elected as the President of Turkey for the third term last Sunday. Erdogan will lead the country with an important position in the international arena for the next five years.</p>



<p>Biden called yesterday Monday to congratulate Erdoğan after winning the election. In this phone conversation, Erdogan reiterated Ankara&#8217;s interest in buying F-16 fighter jets. Biden also informed him of Washington&#8217;s interest in NATO and the Sweden issue. Biden himself told the media about this conversation.</p>



<p>Yesterday, Biden told reporters at the White House, &#8216;I spoke with Erdogan. I congratulated Erdoğan. He (Erdoğan) still wants to do some work on F-16 fighter jets. I told him, we want an agreement with Sweden. Let&#8217;s do it together. We will get back to each other about it.&#8217;</p>



<p>Do you expect Erdoğan to take any initiative on Sweden joining NATO? Reporters ask Biden. In response, Biden said, &#8216;I raised the issue with him (Erdoğan). There will be further discussions between the US and Turkey on this next week.&#8217;</p>



<p>Sweden and Finland have been following the principle of neutrality in international politics for a long time. But after the beginning of the Russian attack on Ukraine in February last year, there was a change in the neutral policy of the two countries. Finland and Sweden think that Moscow can attack their countries as well. So the two countries want to join NATO for advance security. Because, if a member country is attacked, the rest of the NATO members will respond simultaneously. This is the rule of this military alliance.</p>



<p>Sweden and Finland applied to join NATO last year. Türkiye objected. Another NATO rule is that adding new members requires the consent of all existing members. So the initiative got stuck due to the obstruction of NATO member Turkey.</p>



<p>Later, after muddling the waters, Türkiye became flexible about Finland. Removed the objection. As a result, Finland joined NATO. But Erdogan&#8217;s Türkiye is still adamant about Sweden. Sweden&#8217;s application is also pending. So now the US, the most influential member of NATO, is trying to convince Erdogan about Sweden.</p>



<p>Meanwhile, Turkey&#8217;s interest in buying F-16 fighter jets from the US is quite old. The country is also willing to spend 2 billion dollars for this. But the US Congress objected. According to Congress, Ankara has not yet given the green signal for NATO expansion. Apart from this, questions remain about Erdoğan&#8217;s Syria policy and Turkey&#8217;s human rights situation. Therefore, the US Congress does not want to sell F-16 to Ankara for now.</p>



<p>Meanwhile, Erdoğan&#8217;s office issued a statement regarding the phone conversation with Biden. It is said that the two leaders have agreed to deepen cooperation on bilateral issues. This bilateral relationship will play an important role in meeting regional and global challenges.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://max.online.mills.edu/erdogan-wanted-f-16-fighter-jets-biden-gave-conditions/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
